Guide to the Provost Charles Peake Administrative Records, 1967-1971 UA.3.1.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- International Studies Center (UCIS), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  Memos and correspondence on operation of center; memo about predecessor International Studies Program, 1966-1967; statistics on foreign students and faculty, 1967; progress of world culture classes, 1966; minutes of international dimensions committee, 1968; correspondence about Pitt as associate member of Foundation of St. Catherine's, England; memos on establishing UCIS; memos on exchange programs with foreign universities; an area studies certificates; organization chart, 1967.
- International Studies Center, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  Correspondence about bringing International Studies Association to Pitt and other correspondence on UCIS, 1969-1970.
- Johnstown Campus, 1967-1970 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  Correspondence on search committee for new president of Johnstown Campus, 1970; correspondence on plans for Engineering Technology program, 1967-1970; proposal for Engineering program, 1968.
- Johnstown Campus, Library, 1968-1970 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  Library Evaluation Report, 1970; memos about improving library; ground breaking program, October 2, 1969.
- Johnstown Campus, Ecology Program, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Johnstown Campus, 1968-1970 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  Two reports on work of research and training center in vocational rehabilitation, School of Education, 1968-1970; newspaper articles about activities at Johnstown, 1968.
- Johnstown Campus, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  Statements of revenues and expenditures; memos on curriculum and activities; memos on advisory board; letter to Chancellor about rebuttal to charges of social injustice at Johnstown, 1969; memos on Black Action Society; guidelines for operation, 1968; fund campaign reports; planning report, 1968; memos about Life doing a story on Johnstown's Campus's proposal for 4 year program.
- Johnstown Campus, 1968-1970 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  Statement of revenues and expenditures and related memos; memos on search committee for President of campus; paper on development of 4 year program; letters on reappointment to Advisory Board, 1969; memos about operation; letters on Middle State Accreditation, 1968.
- Joint Appointments (Box 21, Folder 4)
  Policy papers, 1969, 1963, 1961 and related memos.
- Law School, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  Correspondence about change from L.L.B. to J.D., 1968; correspondence on appointment of Professor Lawrence Lee to teach international law, 1968.
- Law School, 1966-1970 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  Correspondence on operation of the School, 1966-1970; Status Report 1967-1968; 10 year plan, 1968; annual report, 1967/1968.
- Learning Research and Development Center (LRDC) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  Proposal for R/D Program leading to design of early learning curriculum, April 1968; Long term programs and objectives, May 1968; Proposal to NSF on computer feasibility and requirements for individualization in elementary school, February 1969; Application for proposal of Educational Research Faculty, May 1969; news release and clippings about LRDC.
- Learning Research and Development Center (LRDC) - Clarifying Environment Lab (Box 22, Folder 1)
  "The Responsive Environments Project" by Professor O.K. Moore and A.R. Anderson; proposal for laboratory to Carnegie Corp., 1968; Report to Jack and Jill Foundation for lab school project; "Some Principles for the design of clarifying educational environments" by Moore and Anderson; "The Responsive Environments and Exceptional Children" by Moore; news release on appointment of Moore and articles on "talking typewriter."
- Libraries: Instructional Television, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  Program for development of instructional TV facility; budget and related correspondence.
- Library, 1967-1970 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, 1967-1970; 10 year plan for libraries, 1968; Report: "The Library function redefined" by C.W. Stone, 1967; memo about centralization of library administration, 1968; Proposal to grant faculty status to Librarians, 1969-1970.
- Library and Information Sciences, Graduate School - Information Science, 1968-1969 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  Draft of brochures on Information Science at Pitt, 1968; memos on establishing Communication Science Program, 1968; correspondence on Communication Science Program; correspondence on search committee for faculty; prospectus from University of Michigan Communication Science Program; letter of appointment of Dr. A. Debons; recommendations for a curriculum reprint of Communications of the ACM, Vol. 11/no. 3, March 1968.
- Library and Information Sciences, Graduate School - Interdisciplinary PhD Program, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Memos on University Council on Graduate Studies about new PhD program, 1969; memos on Committee on Doctoral Studies in Information Science, 1969; prospectus for program of advanced studies in Information Science, 1968-1969.
- Library and Information Sciences, Graduate School, 1968-1969 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  Evaluation of PhD program, 1969; Faculty rank for doctoral students; Jack Belzer appointed Chairman ASIS curriculum committee.
- Library and Information Sciences, Graduate School (Box 22, Folder 7)
  Evaluation of PhD program; notes on curriculum innovation; administrative memos.
- Library - Divisional and Professional Library Proposal (Box 22, Folder 8)
  Association of Research Libraries report on relations with Center for Research Libraries, 1966; proposal for division library system at Pitt, 1968; responses from Deans.
- Linguistics Department, 1968-1970 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  Correspondence about administration of Department; memos on training foreign teachers; PhD program.
- Linguistics Department (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Linguistics Department - English House/Institute, 1969-1970 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  Proposed English House for Kuwaiti students to be sponsored by Gulf Oil; plan rejected; proposal for English Language Institute.
- Malcolm-Martin-Marcus Scholars Program, 1969-1970 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  Report on 1968-1969 and 1969-1970 activities; brochures describing program; reports and correspondence to Ford Foundation on grant for program. (Program also known as Project A)
- Mathematical Sciences Proposed Development, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Mathematics Department, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  Development plans, 1970; international conference on topology in Pittsburgh, 1970; projected Department activities, comparison of year 1965/1966; brochure on Math department.
- Mathematics Department (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Mathematics - Search Committee, 1968-1970 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Vitas and references to various candidates for Chairmanship, Math department, 1968-1970.
- Measurement and Evaluation, Office of, 1967-1969 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  Background papers for proposed office, 1967; memos on proposed facility; memos on psychological testing and counseling center; draft proposal for independent psychological testing bureau, 1968; Reports on norms and score distributions-CLEP test, 1967-1968; sophomore class, 1968; 1969 letter advising funds not available for setting up office of measurement and evaluation (set up in 1970).
- Medical School, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  Program for increasing Black enrollment; Proposal: "Toward total justice in medical education and health care" by Henry Finck, 1968.
- Medieval Studies - Proposed Graduate Program, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Middle State Association, 1968-1971 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  Correspondence about evaluation, 1971; minutes of meeting on University steering committee for re-accreditation; newsletters and correspondence from Middle States Association; correspondence about Dr. Peake serving on evaluation team for St. John University.
- Monnett, Lawrence (Box 24, Folder 1)
  Personal correspondence with L. Monnett, former Vice Chancellor of Business Affairs, who went to teach at Pahlavi University, Iran, 1966, as part of development project sponsored by University of Pennsylvania including a description of Iran University project.
- Music Department (Box 24, Folder 2)
  Department memos; music/equipment fees; financial status of department; legal proposal for facility bequeathing personal property to University, 1968; news releases; programs.
- Music Department (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Music Department - Antique Players (Box 24, Folder 4)
  Letter from Dean stating Antique Players not official part of University, 1970; correspondence about funding Players; controversy over funding and scheduling concerts, 1969; programs of the Antique Players concerts.
- NASA - University of Pittsburgh, 1966-1969 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  Memoranda of understanding on NASA training grants; progress reports.
- Nanyang University, Singapore, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  Correspondence with Vice Chancellor R.L. Huang of Nanyang University 1969-1970; Paper: "Exchange program with Nanyang University"; proposal for introducing graduate program in Asian Studies at Nanyang; correspondence about visit of Dr. Huang; correspondence on exchange of staff.
- National Defense Education Act (NDEA) and Pennsylvania Master Plan for Education, 1967-1969 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  Report: "Master plan for Higher Education in Pennsylvania" prepared by State Board of Education, 1967; letters from national legislators supporting NDEA; proposed policy for Penn State's academic planning.
- National Science Foundation, 1968 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  Proposal for Social Science Data Archives for Continuation and Development of Council for Social Science Data Archives, 1968.
- Nepotism Policy, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  Policy statement, 1963, and correspondence on revisions, 1970.
- New Careers Program, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  Proposal for program in School of Social Work; proposal for new Professional Association; new career proposal; proposal for program in College of Arts and Science and School of Education; career development program, 1970.
- Operations, Vice Chancellor - Personnel (Box 24, Folder 11)
  Pay plan for employees, 1967; list of personnel who are administrative specialists; memo on payroll crisis, 1968; personnel activity reports memo from Engineering dean on personnel system, 1968; complaints of classification system; memo about starting steno pool; training program for disadvantaged; grievance procedure; non-faculty salary program.
- Operations, Vice Chancellor - Physical Plant, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  Correspondence and building plans for Forbes Field Area, 1962-1969; plans for a professional center, 1962; initial plans for professional school quadrangle, 1964; correspondence on Law School building.
- Operations, Vice Chancellor - Physical Plant, 1967-1970 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  Memos on space needs including new buildings; news release appointing Hunt Martin Director, Physical Plant, July 29, 1968; memo on reorganization of physical plant, 1968; memos on purchasing anthropology building, architectural drawings of building, 1967.
- Operations, Vice Chancellor - Committee on Non-faculty Personnel, 1968-1969 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  Operating procedures for Committee; reports and correspondence on exceptions to non-faculty categories.
- Oceanography - Accounting (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Oceanography - Virgin Gorda Property, Scaife Foundation (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Oceanography - Frederickson Status Report, Proposal (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Oceanography and Virgin Gorda (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Oceanography - General Materials (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Oceanography and A.F. Frederickson Files (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Oceanography - Chancellor Litchfield Virgin Gorda Files (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Oceanography - Cruise of SABA (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Oceanography Correspondence (Box 26, Folder 5)
  Scope and Contents Notes
  Includes letters with Flax, Harrigan, Staveley, and JA Story.
- Oceanography - Memos on Conferences (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Oceanography - Virgin Gorda Purchase (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Oceanography - Rockefeller, Spilhaus, Steinbach (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Oceanography - Deeter-Ritchey (Box 27, Folder 4)
- Oceanography - Planning File, 1964 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Oceanography - Correspondence and Memos (Box 27, Folder 6)
- PESO: Post-Baccalaureate Educational Service Office, 1968-1969 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  Memo about establishing office, 1968; annual report, 1968/1969; memo on moving office from College of Arts and Sciences to Provost jurisdiction; descriptions of scholarships and fellowships available; recruiting arrangement for various University Law Schools; Career Seminar Arrangements.
- Pennsylvania Master Plan for Higher Education (Box 27, Folder 8)
  Report of progress on master plan, 1966 and related correspondence, 1965-1966; series of brief statements on quality higher education compiled by deans for House subcommittee on higher education, 1969.
- Philosophy Department (Box 28, Folder 1)
- Physical Education, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  Memo stating Professor Marigold Edwards selected to participate in White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health, 1970; memos on student safety at Trees Hall; memo on language requirement for athletes, 1968; note on proposal to combine athletics director and physical education director job, 1968; letters from South Oakland Citizens Council extolling Pitt's Recreation Community program, 1968; memo on physical education requirement for regional campuses, 1969.
- Physics (Box 28, Folder 3)
- Physics - Old Engineering Hall, Scaife gift, and Van de Graaff Accelerator (Box 28, Folder 4)
- Physics - Van de Graaff Accelerator (Box 28, Folder 5)
- Planning and Budget, Vice Chancellor, 1965-1969 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  Shortage of space and letters of complaint from deans about overcrowding, 1965-1969.
- Policy and Position Papers, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  Position Papers on Governance of the University, August 21, 1969; ROTC; and increase in tuition. Policy statements on: admission of minority groups to Schools of Health Professions; Black Action Society; draft on student publications; curriculum reform; "open" university; Black Studies; Student unrest; definition of "centers"; and definition of "I" grades.
- Policy Statements, 1963-1968 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  Memos and policy on conflict of interest, 1968; policy on discrimination, 1962-1963; students' use of alcoholic beverages, 1963; cluster organizations, 1963; conflict of interest in government sponsored research, 1965; proposed policy on drugs; policy on patents, 1966; use of private clubs for University functions, 1966; policy on sabbatical leaves, 1968; smoking in classrooms, 1966; policy on selection of Chancellor, Vice Chancellor of Health Professions and Provost, 1969; policy on payment of social club dues, 1965.
- Political Science Department, 1967-1970 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  Correspondence relating to administration of the department; program in international relations; doctoral program in international relations; papers – "Toward the Democratically Governed University", "The Crisis of the Liberal University", "Academic Integrity and the Prologue Program" by Professor John Chapman.
- Political Science Department (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Program Development and Public Affairs, 1967-1970 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  Draft policy on use of University facilities, 1970; memos on public relations for University; correspondence on Title I Higher Education Act, continuing education proposals; draft of policy for planning and coordination of University functions, 1969; suggested organization and procedures for federal grants, 1968; miscellaneous correspondence.
- Program Development and Public Affairs - Assistant Chancellor, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  Letter from assistant Chancellor Bell to Chancellor outlining role of Urban and Community Services Office; Review of USC office, 1969; memo on working relationships between departments; memo on lack of funds for some projects; clippings on appointment of Dr. Lloyd Bell.
- Protein Research Laboratory, 1966-1968 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  News release on Klaus Hoffman as who synthesized ACTH, September 12, 1966; 1st annual report of protein research laboratory, 1966; Biographical data on Klaus Hoffman; report on laboratory from 1966-1968; correspondence.
- Provost Office, 1967-1970 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  Notice of Dr. Peake's appointment of Provost, 1968 (he was acting provost in 1967); memos on various academic departments, committees, proposed programs; abolishment of Dean of Graduate Faculty, duties given to provost.
- Provost Office, 1967-1970 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  Correspondence on establishing office of Provost and Charles Peake's appointment, 1967; letter from Chancellor on Peake's retirement and appointment of search committee for new Provost, 1970; duties of Provost office personnel and organization charts, 1968.
- Provost, Acting, A. Fidel, 1968-1969 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  Routine correspondence on operations and memos to faculty.
- Psychology Department, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  Departmental Evaluation, 1969; correspondence on Department Head; statement of goals for racial justice, 1969; plan for improvement in teaching performance of graduate student assistants; paper on educational psychology department; administrative memos.
- Psychology Department, 1969-1970 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  Correspondence about selecting a new department chairman; report on training in clinical psychology at Harvard; clinical psychology training, paper by Alfred Miller; paper on faculty appointments in LRDC; plans for developing department; brochures on training in neuropsychobiology.
- Public and Internal Affairs, Graduate School (Box 29, Folder 13)
  Memos to and from C. Peake on progress and projects in GSPIA; proposal for program to help cope with urban crisis, 1969
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School - Institute of Local Government, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  Memos relating to administration of ILG; approval to change name to Institute of Urban Policy and Administration, effective July 1969.
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School, January-June 1969 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  Space requirements for new building; outline of study of U.S. General Accounting office by Dr. Joseph Pois; study of Urban Environmental Research paper; report on teaching in Nigeria; paper on character of Carnegie-Mellon and Pitt Schools of Public Affairs; correspondence and news releases on administration of school.
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School, July-December 1969 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  Memos on recruiting African Americans for main city planning; paper on joint efforts with Carnegie-Mellon School of Public Affairs; proposal for creating a livable urban society; draft constitution of Urban Affiars and related correspondence; correspondence and news releases on administration of school.
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School - Planning, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  Plans and memos on urban Intergroup Relations Program; proposal for urban Intergroup Program.
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  Report on mission to Department of Urban and Regional planning, University of San Carlos, Guatemala; Dean's guidelines for reducing costs; 10 year plan summary; Dean's log of activities; policy on promotion and tenure for GSPIA; Symposium on urban problems by Dean Stone; recommendation for increasing tuition; work program for faculty; department correspondence and news releases.
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School, 1968-1970 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  News releases; memo on conference on community development; report on Malaysian program; report on Nigerian institute; correspondence on proposed cooperative program with North American Rockwell Co.
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School, 1967-1968 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  Paper by Dr. Stone: "The present and future in Urban Affairs Education"; organization chart for GSPIA; proposal for cooperative program with Institute of Administration, Zaria, Nigeria; Discussion paper "careers in rebuilding and management of cities"; memo on professional education in GSPIA's fields; strategy for University's urban thrust; the GSPIA doctoral program in international affairs; request for budget for AID mid-career training program.
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School - Urban Intergroup Relations Program, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  The University's Urban Programs – report to Chancellor, November 1967; Report on CMU's School of Urban and Public Affairs; memo on Nigerian program; memo on HEW financial management intern program; proposal to transfer PhD program in international relations to Department of Political Science; proposed plan for GSPIA future development; recommendation for accepting payments for consulting work; GSPIA activities for improving conditions for minorities; miscellaneous correspondence.
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School - Personnel, 1967-1968 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  Recommendations to appoint Dr. Thomas Davy, Associate Dean, 1967-1968; proposal to appoint Dr. Eric Lincoln to faculty; installation program for Dean Howard; memos on other faculty members; 2 articles by Professor Richman on real estate tax reform.
- Public and International Affairs, Graduate School - Black Student Concerns, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Public Relations Department, 1967-1970 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  Memos on setting up department of News and Publications; other memo on public relations; proposed policy to centralize all publications of academic departments and other University units.
- Public Works Graduate Center, 1969-1970 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  Memos about administration; annual report of Center for 1968-1969; brochures about the Center.
- Public Works Graduate Center, 1966-1968 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  Center proposal with joint sponsorship of School of Engineering and Graduate School of Public Health, November 1966; search for a director, 1968; list of courses; William Korbitz named director; progress report, December 1968; memos about administration.
- Regional Campuses, 1969-1970 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  Memos on student affairs and regional campuses; amendment to Pennsylvania Senate Bill 1304 financing to colleges including Pitt regional campuses, 1970; weekly admission reports; memos on operation; survey of student QPA's; memos on decentralization of regional campuses; minutes of Advisory Board Chairman meetings, 1969.
- Romance Languages (Box 31, Folder 9)
- Romance Languages - NDEA Summer Language Institute, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 1)
- Romance Languages - NDEA Summer Language Institute, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Reserve Officer Training Corps (R.O.T.C.), 1968-1970 (Box 32, Folder 3)
- R.O.T.C., 1968-1970 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  Annual report, Department of Aerospace Studies, 1968; transcripts of meetings, ad hoc committee to study continuance of R.O.T.C., 1969; Report of FAS committee, 1970; reports of R.O.T.C. at various universities, 1969; 2 programs of commissioning ceremonies, 1970.
- R.O.T.C., 1968-1969 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  Syllabus for Air Force R.O.T.C. General Military Course for Freshmen and Sophomores; History of R.O.T.C. at Pitt; agreements signed with Army and Air Force, 1953 and 1965; Change in R.O.T.C. faculty titles, 1969; drafts of position papers on R.O.T.C., 1969; defense of Army R.O.T.C. program from Professor Clagett, Military Science, 1968.
- R.O.T.C., 1969-1970 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  Proposed new R.O.T.C. curriculum, 1969; correspondence on including R.O.T.C. in Freshman Orientation, 1969; memos about ad hoc faculty committee to investigate alternative program, 1969-1970.
- R.O.T.C., 1969 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  Reports from Brown University, Tulane, Ohio State, Cornell, Dartmouth, and Yale on their R.O.T.C. programs, 1969.
- R.O.T.C., 1968 (Box 32, Folder 8)